Guide to the Leonard Bacon Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1906-1954; Series II; 17.18; (41 boxes)
  - The Lusiads, by Luis de Camões. Translation., undated; 5 (Box 52)
  - The Lusiads, by Luis de Camões. Translation., undated; 6 (Box 53)
  - The Lusiads, by Luis de Camões. Translation., undated; 6 (Box 54)
  - The Lusiads, by Luis de Camões. Translation., undated; 3 (Box 55)
    Proofs
  - The Lusiads, index cards, undated (Box 56)
  - The Lusiads, index cards, undated (Box 57)
  - Military Dictionary Project, 1940-1944; 8 (Box 58)
    Autograph and typescript, with some correspondence
  - The Misanthrope, by Moliére. Translation., undated; 10 (Box 59)
    Autograph, typescript and typescript carbons
  - The Mound-Builders, 1926 June 25 (Box 59)
    Typescript carbon, 35 leaves
  - "The Nets of Psyche", 1943; 2 (Box 60)
    Typescript original, 29 leaves
    Typescript carbon, 29 leaves
  - "New Guinea's Stamp", undated (Box 60)
    Autographs, 21 leaves
  - "New Words to Old Music", undated (Box 60)
    Autograph, 3 leaves
    Typescript carbon, 3 leaves
  - "The Obscure Wood", undated; 3 (Box 60)
  - "October 2nd, 1933" (Box 60)
    Autograph, 9 leaves, draft
    Autograph, 9 leaves, copy
  - "The Princess, A Medley", undated; 3 (Box 81)
    Autograph and typescript carbon
  - "Psychology", 1945-1949 (Box 60)
    Miscellaneous paper, with some correspondence
  - "Red Network", undated (Box 60)
    Typescript
  - "The Religious Groundhogs", 1952 (Box 60)
    Autograph, typescript and typescript carbon with correspondence
  - "Rezanov", undated (Box 60)
  - "Rimbaud", undated (Box 61)
    Notes & drafts
  - "Rhyme and Punishment", undated (Box 61)
  - "Russian Nursery Rhymes", undated (Box 61)
  - "Salmon-Fishing", undated (Box 61)
    Typescript carbon, 1 leave, 2 variants
  - "Sappho," photostatic copy, undated (Box 81)
  - The Scrannel Pipe, undated (Box 61)
  - Semi-Centennial (1st version), undated; 3 (Box 61)
  - Semi-Centennial (2nd version), undated; 4 (Box 62)
  - Semi-Centennial, undated; 2 (Box 62)
    Typescript and setting typescript
  - Semi-Centennial, undated; 3 (Box 63)
    Typescript copy, page proof and galley proofs
  - "Smirt, an Urbane Nightmare, by Branch Cabell", undated (Box 64)
    Autograph, 4 leaves, book review
  - "Some Apologetic Remarks on Prosody", undated (Box 64)
    Typescript carbon, 7 leaves
  - "The Song of Roland", 1923 (Box 64)
    Typescript original, 19 leave, essay
  - "Stephen Vincent Benét", 1935-1943 (Box 64)
    Typescript carbon, 7 leaves, written 1935
    Typescript carbon, 6 leaves
    Autograph, 14 leaves, draft
    Autograph, 14 leaves, fair copy
  - "Stephen Vincent Benét: Introduction", undated (Box 64)
    Autograph, 17 leaves
    Typescript original, 10 leaves
    Typescript carbon, 10 leaves, with manuscript corrections
  - Sunderland Capture and Other Poems, 1940 (Box 64)
    Setting typescript original, 54 leaves
  - "The Tragedy of Dunbar," autograph, undated; 2 (Box 81)
  - "The Trail of the Rooster", undated (Box 64)
    Typescript carbon, 18 leaves
    Typescript carbon, 20 leaves
  - Tumanean, Hovhannes. Anúsh, undated (Box 64)
    Typescript carbon, 40 leaves, translation
  - Ulug Beg, undated; 3 (Box 64)
    Synopsis, typescript carbon, 20 leaves
    Typescript, bound
    Typescript carbon, bound
  - Ulug Beg, undated (Box 65)
  - "University, A Story of Profound Changes", undated (Box 65)
    Autograph, 35 leaves
  - "Unreal City", undated (Box 65)
    Autograph, 2 leaves, draft
    Autograph, 2 leaves, fair copy
    Typescript, 2 leaves, with manuscript corrections
    Typescript carbon, 2 leaves
  - "Variation on Browning and A. France: Rome, 60 A.D.", undated (Box 65)
    Autograph, 2 leaves
  - Voyage of Autoleon, undated; 4 (Box 65)
    Autograph drafts, typescript, and typescript carbon, corrected
  - "War, A Farce-Tragedy", undated (Box 65)
    Typescript original, 9 leaves
  - "West of Worcester, by R-b-rt Fr-st: and other parodies", 1915 August 23 (Box 65)
    Typescript, 11 leaves, 2 carbons
  - Wright, Austin. Islandia: Introduction, 1942 (Box 66)
    Autograph, typescript and typescript carbon drafts with correspondence and proof
  - "The Year's Comedy", undated (Box 66)
    Typescript original, 5 leaves
  - Zwölf Tage und Zwölf Nächte, undated; 2 (Box 66)
    Autograph, 35 leaves, translation part only
    With typescript carbon, of German original
  - Essays and book reviews, undated; 8 (Box 67)
  - Essays and book reviews, undated; 7 (Box 68)
  - Poems, undated; 17 (Box 69)
  - Poems, undated; 8 (Box 70)
  - Poems, undated; 7 (Box 71)
  - Poems, undated; 9 (Box 72)
  - Poems, undated; 5 (Box 73)
  - Poems, undated; 8 (Box 74)
  - Notebooks "I" - "XVI", 1935-1940; 17 (Box 75)
  - Notebooks "XVII" - "XXXVI", 1940-1951; 21 (Box 76)
  - Notebooks "XXXVII" - "XXXVIII," untitled, 1952-1953, undated; 7 (Box 77)
  - Diaries, 1907-1937, undated; 3 (Box 77)
  - Journal - Hawaiian, 1939 (Box 78)
  - Journal, 1951-1953; 3 (Box 78)
  - Miscellaneous fragmentary and unidentified manuscripts, undated; 11 (Box 79)
  - Miscellaneous fragmentary and unidentified manuscripts, and writings of others, undated; 19 (Box 80)
- Printed Material, Series III; 1.67; (4 boxes)
  Series III is comprised of printed versions of Leonard Bacon's writings, as well as periodicals, pamphlets, reprints, bulletins, programs, newspaper clippings and other printed ephemera collected by Bacon.
  - Printed versions of Leonard Bacon's writings, 15 (Box 82)
  - Printed versions of Leonard Bacon's writings, 12 (Box 83)
  - Periodicals, pamphlets, and reprints, 33 (Box 84)
  - Bulletins, programs, ephemera, and newspaper clippings, 17 (Box 85)
- Other Papers, 1917-1951; Series IV; 0.42; (1 box)
  Series IV contains scrapbooks, personal papers and effects, and photographs. It also contains an original drawing by Charles Child, inscribed to Leonard Bacon.
  - Scrapbooks, 1923-1948 (Box 86)
  - Personal papers and effects, 1917-1951; 6 (Box 86)
  - Photographs, undated; 2 (Box 86)
  - Child, Charles. Original drawing, framed, inscribed to Leonard Bacon, Christmas 1936. (Box 92 Art Storage)
- Oversize, 1.25; (5 boxes)
  - The Furioso, manuscript (Series II), undated; 2 (Box 87)
  - The Lay of the Cid, manuscript (Series II), undated (Box 88)
  - The Mound-Builders, manuscript (Series II), undated; 2 (Box 88)
  - Ulug Beg, manuscript (Series II), undated; 4 (Box 89)
  - The Voyage of Autoleon, manuscript (Series II), undated (Box 90)
  - Poems (Series II), 1914-1918, undated; 2 (Box 90)
  - Unidentified writings (Series II), undated; 2 (Box 90)
  - Scrapbooks (Series IV), 1924-1948; 2 (Box 91)
  - Yale University honorary degree certificate (Series IV) (Box 91)
  - Photograph of school group (Series IV), circa 1898 (Box 91)